[Alert Icon Icon of an exclamation point in a triangle.

**Other cause:** TCTD Routes 60X/70X service suspended

**Other cause:** Routes 1X, 4, 6, 8, 18, 30X on detour July 22-28 for Hoopla 2024

View Service Alerts](https://www.cherriots.org/alerts/)

* English

* [Services, Maps, and Routes Arrow Down Icon Icon of a downward-facing arrow.](#primary-menu--item-2)
* [Fares and Passes Arrow Down Icon Icon of a downward-facing arrow.](#primary-menu--item-3)

* Trip Planner
    ------------

* Services, Maps, and Routes
    --------------------------

    ### Services
    
    [### Cherriots Local
    
    Safe, friendly, reliable bus service throughout Salem-Keizer
    
    Cherriots Local Bus Icon Icon of a bus from the front](https://www.cherriots.org/local/)
    
    [### Cherriots Regional
    
    Routes linking Salem to the Mid-Willamette Valley region
    
    Cherriots Regional Icon Icon of map markers connected with dotted lines.](https://www.cherriots.org/regional/)
    
    [### Cherriots LIFT
    
    Paratransit service for people with qualifying disabilities
    
    Cherriots LIFT Icon Icon of a person with mobility device boarding a bus](https://www.cherriots.org/lift/)
    
    [### Cherriots Shop and Ride
    
    Dial-a-Ride service and Shopper Shuttle (now suspended) for seniors and people with disabilities
    
    Shop and Ride Icon Icon of a moving shopping cart](https://www.cherriots.org/shopandride/)
    
    [### Commuter Options
    
    Empowering people to navigate their community in ways that improve livability and quality of life
    
    Trip Choice Icon Icon of people walking, riding a bike, and carpooling](https://www.cherriots.org/transportationoptions/)
    
    [### Travel Training
    
    FREE educational opportunities to access your community using transit
    
    Travel Training Icon Travel Training Icon](https://www.cherriots.org/traveltraining/)
    
    [### Park and Ride Locations
    
    Catch the bus, connect with your carpool, or finish your commute by bike
    
    Park and Ride Icon Icon of the letter P in a circle](https://www.cherriots.org/parkandride/)
    
    ### Explore
    
    [### System Map
    
    Explore routes, stops and transit centers with our interactive map
    
    System Map Icon Icon of a map](https://www.cherriots.org/system-map/)
    
    [### Service Alerts
    
    Find the latest information on detours and other service updates
    
    Alert Icon Icon of an exclamation point in a triangle](https://www.cherriots.org/alerts/)
    
    [### Transit Centers
    
    Centers where buses meet to make it easy to transfer
    
    Transit Centers Icon Icon of multiple buses lined up](https://www.cherriots.org/transitcenters/)
    
    ### All Routes
    
    Routes Select Route 1X - Wilsonville / Salem Express 2 - Market / Brown 3 - Portland Road 4 - State Street 5 - Center Street 6 - Fairview Industrial 7 - Mission Street 8 - 12th / Liberty 9 - Cherry / River Road 10X - Woodburn / Salem Express 11 - Lancaster / Verda 12 - Hayesville Drive 13 - Silverton Road 14 - Windsor Island Road 16 - Wallace Road 17 - Edgewater Street 18 - 12th / Liberty 19 - Broadway / River Road 20X - North Marion County / Salem Express 21 - South Commercial 22 - Kuebler Link 23 - Lansing / Hawthorne 26 - Glen Creek / Orchard Heights 27 - Glen Creek / Eola 30X - Santiam / Salem Express 40X - Polk County / Salem Express 45 - Central Polk County 50X - Dallas / Salem Express 80X - Wilsonville / Keizer Express Arrow Down Icon Icon of a downward-facing arrow.

* Fares and Passes
    ----------------

    [### Fares and Passes
    
    Find the price of all passes for Cherriots Local, Cherriots Regional, and Cherriots LIFT
    
    Fares Icon Icon of a dollar sign on a bus pass](https://www.cherriots.org/fares/)
    
    [### Reduced Fare ID
    
    Reduced fares for seniors, people with disabilities, and Medicare card holders
    
    Reduced Fare Icon Icon of a dollar sign with an arrow pointing down](https://www.cherriots.org/reducedfare/)
    
    [### Group Pass program
    
    A benefit to attract talent, stay competitive, and go green
    
    DBE Program Icon Icon of a hand supporting two people](https://www.cherriots.org/grouppass/)
    
    [### Umo
    
    Paying your fare just got easier!](https://www.cherriots.org/umo/)
    
    | Cherriots Local and Cherriots Regional | Full Fare | Reduced Fare |
    | --- | --- | --- |
    | One-Ride | $1.60 | $0.80 |
    | Day Pass | $3.25 | $1.50 |
    | 30 Day Pass or Month Pass | $45.00 | $22.50 |
    | Annual Pass (Cherriots Tap Card or Umo Mobility App) | $540.00 | $270.00 |
    
    | Cherriots LIFT and Cherriots Dial-a-Ride | Fare |
    | --- | --- |
    | One-Ride (_one way_) | $3.20 |
    | Universal LIFT Month Pass (Cherriots Tap Card or Umo Mobility App) | $90.00 |
    
    **Note: Youth ages 0-18 may ride all Cherriots services for free. No pass is required.**

* Rider Guide
    -----------

    [### Health at Cherriots: combating coronavirus
    
    We're taking steps to keep you safe
    
    Alert Icon Icon of an exclamation point in a triangle](https://www.cherriots.org/health/)
    
    [### Getting Started Riding the Bus
    
    The basics of how to have a safe, comfortable ride
    
    Getting Started Icon Icon of a person boarding a bus](https://www.cherriots.org/howtoride/)
    
    [### Travel Training
    
    FREE educational opportunities to access your community using transit
    
    Travel Training Icon Travel Training Icon](https://www.cherriots.org/traveltraining/)
    
    [### Trip Planner Help
    
    Instructions and tips for using our Trip Planner
    
    Trip Planner Help Icon Icon of the letter I in a circle](https://www.cherriots.org/tripplannerhelp/)
    
    [### Holiday Service
    
    Bus service levels for upcoming holidays
    
    Holiday Icon Icon of a star marked on a calendar](https://www.cherriots.org/holidays/)
    
    [### Safety
    
    Tips to make it a safe trip, every time
    
    Safety Icon Icon of a construction cone](https://www.cherriots.org/safety/)
    
    [### Accessibility
    
    How Cherriots makes services accessible to everyone, regardless of ability
    
    Accessible Icon Icon of person in mobility device](https://www.cherriots.org/accessibility/)
    
    [### Security
    
    Rules of the road to make a pleasant trip for all riders
    
    Security Icon Icon of a security badge](https://www.cherriots.org/security/)

* About Us
    --------

    [### Our Organization
    
    Creating community connections
    
    Organization Icon Icon of the Cherriots logo](https://www.cherriots.org/organization/)
    
    [### Accountability and Transparency
    
    Access to our records, reports, and financial documents
    
    Accountability Icon Icon of a magnifying glass over a report](https://www.cherriots.org/accountability/)
    
    [### Equity and Access
    
    Cherriots respects civil rights and creates access for all
    
    Equity Icon Icon of people standing on blocks to be same height](https://www.cherriots.org/equity/)
    
    [### Projects
    
    Current and future plans for enhancing service for our riders
    
    Project Icon Icon of a gear and a piece of paper](https://www.cherriots.org/projects/)
    
    [### News
    
    The latest news and updates from Cherriots
    
    News Icon Icon of a newspaper](https://www.cherriots.org/news/)
    
    [### Board of Directors
    
    The legal governing body of Cherriots
    
    Board of Directors Icon Icon of people sitting around a table](https://www.cherriots.org/board/)
    
    [### Careers
    
    Our employees are our greatest investment
    
    Careers Icon Icon of a briefcase](https://www.cherriots.org/careers/)
    
    [### Strategic Plan
    
    Delivering valued mobility options that inspire community pride
    
    Reports Icon Icon of a report doument](https://www.cherriots.org/strategicplan/)

* Planificador de Viajes
    ----------------------

* Servicios, Mapas, y Rutas
    -------------------------

    ### Servicios
    
    [### Cherriots Local
    
    Servicio seguro, amable, y fiable en el área de Salem-Keizer
    
    Cherriots Local Bus Icon Icon of a bus from the front](https://www.cherriots.org/es/local/)
    
    [### Cherriots Regional
    
    Rutas conectando Salem a la región del Valle Willamette
    
    Cherriots Regional Icon Icon of map markers connected with dotted lines.](https://www.cherriots.org/es/regional/)
    
    [### Cherriots LIFT
    
    Servicio paratránsito para personas con discapacidades elegibles
    
    Cherriots LIFT Icon Icon of a person with mobility device boarding a bus](https://www.cherriots.org/es/lift/)
    
    [### Cherriots Shop and Ride
    
    Servicios para la gente mayor y personas con discapacidades: Solicitud de Servicio por Teléfono y Transporte para Ir de Compras (suspendido)
    
    Shop and Ride Icon Icon of a moving shopping cart](https://www.cherriots.org/es/shopandride/)
    
    ### Explorar
    
    [### Mapa del sistema
    
    System Map Icon Icon of a map](https://www.cherriots.org/es/systemmap-es/)
    
    [### Alertas del Servicio
    
    Alertas en vivo acerca de todos los servicios de Cherriots
    
    Alert Icon Icon of an exclamation point in a triangle](https://www.cherriots.org/es/servicealerts/)
    
    [### Centros de Tránsito
    
    Centros que facilitan transferencias fáciles
    
    Transit Centers Icon Icon of multiple buses lined up](https://www.cherriots.org/es/transitcenters/)
    
    [### Capacitación de Viajes
    
    Oportunidades educativas GRATUITAS para acceder a su comunidad usando el autobús
    
    Travel Training Icon Travel Training Icon](https://www.cherriots.org/es/traveltraining/)
    
    ### Todas las Rutas
    
    Routes Select Route 1X - Wilsonville / Salem Express 2 - Market / Brown 3 - Portland Road 4 - State Street 5 - Center Street 6 - Fairview Industrial 7 - Mission Street 8 - 12th / Liberty 9 - Cherry / River Road 10X - Woodburn / Salem Express 11 - Lancaster / Verda 12 - Hayesville Drive 13 - Silverton Road 14 - Windsor Island Road 16 - Wallace Road 17 - Edgewater Street 18 - 12th / Liberty 19 - Broadway / River Road 20X - North Marion County / Salem Express 21 - South Commercial 22 - Kuebler Link 23 - Lansing / Hawthorne 26 - Glen Creek / Orchard Heights 27 - Glen Creek / Eola 30X - Santiam / Salem Express 40X - Polk County / Salem Express 45 - Central Polk County 50X - Dallas / Salem Express 80X - Wilsonville / Keizer Express Arrow Down Icon Icon of a downward-facing arrow.

* Tarifas y Pases
    ---------------

    [### Tarifas y Pases
    
    Encuentre el precio de todos los pases de Cherriots Local, Cherriots Regional, y Cherriots LIFT
    
    Fares Icon Icon of a dollar sign on a bus pass](https://www.cherriots.org/es/fares/)
    
    [### Tarjeta de Identificación para Tarifa Reducida
    
    Tarifas reducidas para personas mayores, personas con discapacidades, y titulares de tarjetas de Medicare
    
    Reduced Fare Icon Icon of a dollar sign with an arrow pointing down](https://www.cherriots.org/es/reducedfare/)
    
    | Cherriots Local y Cherriots Regional | Tarifa Normal | Tarifa Reducida |
    | --- | --- | --- |
    | Un-Viaje | $1.60 | $0.80 |
    | Pase del Día | $3.25 | $1.50 |
    | Pase de Mes y Pase de 30 Días | $45.00 | $22.50 |
    | Pase Anual (Cherriots Tap Card o Umo Mobility App) | $540.00 | $270.00 |
    
    | Cherriots LIFT y Cherriots Dial-a-Ride | Tarifa |
    | --- | --- |
    | Un-Viaje (_solo ida_) | $3.20 |
    
    **Nota: Los jóvenes de 0 a 18 años pueden viajar en todos los servicios de Cherriots de forma gratuita. No se requiere pase.**

* Guía Para Pasajeros
    -------------------

    [### La salud a Cherriots: combatiendo al coronavirus
    
    Estamos tomando medidas para mantenerlos a todos seguros
    
    Alert Icon Icon of an exclamation point in a triangle](https://www.cherriots.org/es/health/)
    
    [### Cómo Viajar por el Autobús Cherriots
    
    Los conocimientos básicos sobre cómo tener un viaje seguro y cómodo
    
    Getting Started Icon Icon of a person boarding a bus](https://www.cherriots.org/es/howtoride/)
    
    [### Capacitación de Viajes
    
    Oportunidades educativas GRATUITAS para acceder a su comunidad usando el autobús
    
    Travel Training Icon Travel Training Icon](https://www.cherriots.org/es/traveltraining/)
    
    [### Ayuda para el Planificador de Viaje
    
    Instrucciones y consejos para usar nuestro Planificador de Viaje
    
    Trip Planner Help Icon Icon of the letter I in a circle](https://www.cherriots.org/es/tripplannerhelp/)
    
    [### Servicio de los Días Feriados
    
    Servicios disponibles en los próximos días feriados
    
    Holiday Icon Icon of a star marked on a calendar](https://www.cherriots.org/es/holidays/)
    
    [### Seguridad: Como Estar Seguro
    
    Consejos para que el viaje sea seguro, todas las veces
    
    Safety Icon Icon of a construction cone](https://www.cherriots.org/es/safety/)
    
    [### Accessibilidad
    
    Cómo Cherriots hace los servicios accesibles a toda la gente, no importa la habilidad
    
    Accessible Icon Icon of person in mobility device](https://www.cherriots.org/es/accessibility/)
    
    [### Seguridad: Reglas para Todos
    
    Reglas que haga un buen viaje para todos
    
    Security Icon Icon of a security badge](https://www.cherriots.org/es/security/)

* Acerca de Cherriots
    -------------------

    ### En español:
    
    [### Carreras
    
    Nuestros empleados son nuestra gran inversión
    
    Careers Icon Icon of a briefcase](https://www.cherriots.org/es/careers/)
    
    ### En inglés:
    
    [### Our Organization
    
    Creating community connections
    
    Organization Icon Icon of the Cherriots logo](https://www.cherriots.org/organization/)
    
    [### Equity and Access
    
    Cherriots respects civil rights and creates access for all
    
    Equity Icon Icon of people standing on blocks to be same height](https://www.cherriots.org/equity/)

Search Icon Icon of magnifying glass.

Privacy Policy
==============

What information we collect and how we use that information

Thank you for visiting the Cherriots website at Cherriots.org (the "Site") and reviewing our privacy policy. This privacy policy is effective as of December 27, 2010, and applies only to the Site. It is designed to assist you in understanding how we collect and use the personal information you provide to us, and to assist you in making informed decisions when using our Site. Cherriots respects the privacy of your personal information.

This privacy policy covers the following areas:

* What information we collect through our Site;
* How we use the information;
* With whom we may share the information;
* What choices you have about our collection, use, and disclosure of the information;
* What security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of information under our control; and
* How you can correct any inaccuracies in your information.

### 1\. Information collection

Cherriots collects information on the Site at two different stages. First, we use server logs to collect anonymous, aggregate information (such as browser type, ISP, IP address, referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, number of clicks) from all visitors to the Site. Our Site also uses a standard technology called "cookies" to collect information about how the Site is used. Information gathered through cookies may include the pages viewed and the amount of time spent at the Site. This type of information is typically not linked to any personally identifiable information and is used primarily in the aggregate to generate statistical reports about the use of our Site. Cherriots does reserve the right to connect information collected through its server logs with other personally identifiable information.

Second, we require certain information when you use services available on the Site. For example, when you contact us by email, we may collect your email address and any other personal information you provide. When you subscribe to one of our electronic newsletters, you must provide your name and a valid email address. You may also provide your address, telephone number and organizational affiliation, and you may choose to create a password for managing your account.

To unsubscribe from any of our email lists, simply click on the link labeled "unsubscribe" at the top of any email from us, or contact us at [info@cherriots.org](mailto:info@cherriots.org).

### 2\. Personal information of children under 13

Cherriots complies with the requirements of the Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) and the FTC's Rule interpreting COPPA (16 CFR § 512). The Site is not directed to children, and we do not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information on the Site from children under 13 years of age.

### 3\. Use of your personal information

Cherriots does not sell, rent or disclose personally identifiable information to any third party not affiliated with us, except for disclosure to service providers who may assist us in such areas as data storage, and in accordance with Paragraph 4 below. However, users should be aware that Cherriots is a public agency and personal information provided to Cherriots may be subject to disclosure in accordance with public records laws. Information in anonymous, aggregated form may be shared freely. Cherriots will not use your personal information to send you unsolicited commercial offers. However, we may need to contact you for certain purposes, as for example in response to your inquiry, or with a message regarding the status of the Site.

### 4\. Disclosure of personal information as required by law

We will disclose personal information when required by law, or if we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to (a) comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on us, (b) protect and defend our rights, or (c) protect the rights, property, and other interests of our users or others.

### 5\. Links

The Site contains links to other sites. Cherriots is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of these other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our Site and to read the privacy statements and terms/conditions of use for each and every site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by the Cherriots Site.

### 6\. Security

We take reasonable precautions to protect your information. For example, we encrypt certain communications through our Site with 128-bit encryption, the industry standard for strong encryption. However, given the nature of the Internet and the fact that network security measures are not infallible, we cannot guarantee the security of your information.

If you have any questions about the security at our Site, you can send an email to the webmaster at [info@cherriots.org](mailto:info@cherriots.org).

### 7\. Correcting, updating, deleting and deactivating personal information

If your information changes, you may contact us to correct, update or delete and deactivate our records.

### 8\. Notification of changes

Cherriots may modify the terms of this privacy policy at any time by updating this posting. If this privacy policy changes materially so that we are going to use your personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection, or if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that affect customer information already stored in our database, we will prominently post a notice on the main page and other pages to alert you about the change. You should check the Site periodically to remain informed of the latest version of the privacy policy.

### 9\. Contact information

Cherriots  
Attention: Webmaster  
555 Court St. NE, Suite 5230  
Salem, OR 97301  
503-588-2424  

### Would you like to read our Terms of Use?

Would you like to read our Terms of Use?

Contact Us
----------

**Email:** [info@cherriots.org](mailto:info@cherriots.org)  
**Customer Service:** 503-588-2877  
**Administrative Offices:** 503-588-2424  
**Oregon Relay Network:** TTY 1-800-735-2900 

555 Court St. NE, Suite 5230  
Salem, OR 97301  

© Salem Area Mass Transit District (SAMTD) | All rights reserved.
